<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>The blog of Iain C Docherty</title>
 <link href="http://spacebotwar.com:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://spacebotwar.com:4000"/>
 <updated>2013-12-23T11:15:38+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://spacebotwar.com:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Iain C Docherty</name>
   <email>spacebotwar@iain-docherty.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>First Post</title>
   <link href="http://spacebotwar.com:4000/blog/2013/12/20/first-post.html"/>
   <updated>2013-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://spacebotwar.com:4000/blog/2013/12/20/first-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;SpaceBotWar is a game that is influenced by many years of playing computer games several years of writing computer games, and more years than I care to admit to, creating software applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main influence for SpaceBotWar comes from a game call &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robotwar&quot;&gt;RobotWar&lt;/a&gt; which you will see was around nearly ten years before the Internet was ‘turned on’. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robotwar&quot;&gt;RobotWar&lt;/a&gt; you controlled the movements of your robot in an attempt to compete against other robots. Of course what was being tested here was the programming skill of the players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept for the full game is quite simple and has influence from many other on-line games, you build an empire, using resources that you collect or steal, you defend your base against attackers and you try to attack other players and Artificial Intelligence players in turn. In that respect it is not much different to many games out there such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kixeye.com/game/vegaconflict&quot;&gt;Vega Conflict&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this, if you happen to be away from keyboard (AFK) when you are attacked then you rely on the pre-programmed actions built into the game to do your defending for you. What if you were able to influence that defence, what if &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; were able to write the code that controls your defence? What if you were able to write the code that determines how your spaceships move, how they dodge missiles, how they track down and work together to attack the enemy ships. That ability to program your empires actions is what SpaceBotWar is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have a vision for the final game, a brief outline of which I have shared with you, I will expand on the ideas in later blogs. For now I would like to share my idea for an initial ‘alpha’ version of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version of the game will investigate the ability of players to control a fleet of space ships, say six ships. All ships will have the same characteristics, speed, turning speed, weapons. Players can enter their fleets into weekly tournaments where fleets compete against each other. These fleets being identical will only differ in their programming. What will be tested then in the tournaments will actually be the fitness of the programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week the tournament will &lt;em&gt;rank&lt;/em&gt; these programs based on the outcome of their individual matches against each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Version 1 will have the following main features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players will be able to write control programs for their fleets&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tournaments will be made up of many matches between pairs of fleets.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The winners of a tournament will be the fleets (programs) which win the most matches.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Matches will be run throughout the week on a schedule&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Anyone may watch, in real time, any match that is currently running.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Match will show the real-time movement of ships, missiles and blast damage.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A league table will be presented to show the relative ranking of programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition the following secondary features will be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different languages will be available to program fleets, certainly Perl, Python, Ruby.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Other languages may be added as they are implemented.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Programs will be able to be edited on-line where they will be compiled, tested and debugged.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Since programs will be ‘public-domain’ then anyone can clone an existing program and adapt and modify it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim to foster an environment where people can swap ideas and build on what other people have implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is still early days, but we also hope to introduce a scheme to rate individuals based on how well their programs, or other programs which were based on them, are doing in the rating system. A form of ‘Qudos’ if you like. A recognition of programmers with the best skill. I will describe how I think this will work in a later Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
